<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Content on PHI 14f</title>
    <link>https://chreliot.github.io/phi14f/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Content on PHI 14f</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2020 15:26:52 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://chreliot.github.io/phi14f/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Test 1 Questions</title>
      <link>https://chreliot.github.io/phi14f/tests/test-1-questions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2020 14:14:07 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chreliot.github.io/phi14f/tests/test-1-questions/</guid>
      <description>Here are the questions for the first test. The test will be from a subset of these questions. For each question, write at least five sentences (minimum) and perhaps a bit more than five. Write concisely and informatively. If there is more than one part to the question, make sure to answer all the parts.
 What is Blackburn&amp;rsquo;s “middle-ground” defense of philosophy. What is Blackburn&amp;rsquo;s “low-ground” defense of philosophy. In Apology, what does Socrates say is the greatest good for a human being (“a man”), and what does he say that supports that?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Topic 5: Happiness</title>
      <link>https://chreliot.github.io/phi14f/topics/happiness/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2020 12:39:02 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chreliot.github.io/phi14f/topics/happiness/</guid>
      <description>From Epicureans to the present, some philosophers have thought that the meaning of life might lie in seeking happiness. We consider a classic expression of this view in anglophone philosophy, and then some criticisms of it.
Reading  John Stuart Mill, from Utilitarianism, 1861. Read, in the following order:  the first section of Chapter 2 “What Utilitarianism Is”, from pages 4 into 5; Chapter 4 “What sort of proof can be given for the principle of utility?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Topic 4: Stoicism</title>
      <link>https://chreliot.github.io/phi14f/topics/stoicism/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 17:42:50 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chreliot.github.io/phi14f/topics/stoicism/</guid>
      <description>The next few topics are specific, positive accounts of the meaning of life. The first one is the ancient — and currently popular — view called Stoicism. Coming to understand what is really good, the Stoics argued, and how the nature of goodness and happiness are rooted in nature, could lead us toward perfect lives.
Reading  Epictetus, The Handbook, PDF available on Blackboard &amp;gt; Course Documents.  See also   “How Not to Panic During the Coronavirus Pandemic: Welcome Hard Times Like a Stoic,” by Brigid Delaney</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assignment 1</title>
      <link>https://chreliot.github.io/phi14f/assignments/assignment-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2020 12:17:01 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chreliot.github.io/phi14f/assignments/assignment-1/</guid>
      <description>Your main task is to identify and reconstruct an argument about the meaning of life and then critically evaluate it.
Based on how well you think it works for this task, choose one of the following: (1) the Steve Jobs speech, or (2) a different speech or text you&amp;rsquo;ve found and cleared with me in advance. That will be your “source text.”
From your source text, reconstruct a statement of the form “The meaning of life is …” or “The way to live is ….</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Topic 3: Religion and Science</title>
      <link>https://chreliot.github.io/phi14f/topics/relsci/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2020 12:33:11 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chreliot.github.io/phi14f/topics/relsci/</guid>
      <description>Our questions about the meaning of life led to its relationships to two main human institutions from which people seek understanding — religion (especially theology) and science. In this section, we consider the relationship between questions about the meaning of life and the capacities of these institutions.
Reading  Brown, Delwin. 1971. “Process Philosophy and the Question of Life&amp;rsquo;s Meaning Religious Studies 7(1): 13-29, 10 pages of reading. Access through Axinn Library login here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Topic 2: Questions about the Meaning of Life</title>
      <link>https://chreliot.github.io/phi14f/topics/meaning/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 11:55:32 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chreliot.github.io/phi14f/topics/meaning/</guid>
      <description>In Plato&amp;rsquo;s Gorgias we encountered two conflicting versions of the meaning of life, and we discussed philosophy as an approach to questions. Now we turn our focus to what&amp;rsquo;s puzzling about the meaning of life. We can ask “What&amp;rsquo;s the meaning of life?” But that is just the opening move. What are the other questions we might want to ask in order to begin to answer that question? When we face difficult problems, often understanding the question is half the battle!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Topic 1: Philosophy</title>
      <link>https://chreliot.github.io/phi14f/topics/philosophy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2020 12:08:29 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chreliot.github.io/phi14f/topics/philosophy/</guid>
      <description>One of the most prominent living philosophers, Martha Nussbaum, was recently asked “How would you define the role of a philosopher in today’s world?” She answered:
 I wouldn’t. There are so many good ways to engage with the world, and each philosopher should figure it out for herself. I don’t like telling others what to do.
 Still, philosophy has a history. And its history involves people doing specific things and calling them “philosophy,” and not calling other things “philosophy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interpreting Grades</title>
      <link>https://chreliot.github.io/phi14f/info/interpreting-grades/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2020 19:55:28 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chreliot.github.io/phi14f/info/interpreting-grades/</guid>
      <description>This note about grading and interpreting grades just adds some detail to what the course syllabus already says about grading.
 4-point scale Writing assignment grades Test grades Overall course grades    4-point scale Grades in this course are assigned and calculated using Hofstra&amp;rsquo;s 4-point scale (described here in the Hofstra Bulletin). Following the Bulletin, the alphabetical grades, including plus (+) and minus (–), have the following 4-point scale values (and vice versa):</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Participation Rubric</title>
      <link>https://chreliot.github.io/phi14f/info/participation-rubric/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2019 21:25:39 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chreliot.github.io/phi14f/info/participation-rubric/</guid>
      <description>This is the participation rubric to be used for grading participation in this course. Read it as saying “A student who demonstrates … earns a grade of X,” where X is the letter grade at the top of the column.1
   A B C D F     Active role in discussions, drawing on texts Regular, constructive participation drawing on texts Inconsistent constructive participation based on texts Vague comments reflecting limited engagement with texts Persistent lack of engagement with texts   Full preparation for approximately every class Substantial preparation, normally Inconsistent evidence of preparation Rare evidence of participation No positive evidence of participation   Success at advancing level and depth of discussion, persistently Regular contributions based on assigned material, which sometimes improve discussion and never diminish it Rare or no significant contribution to the level of discussion while not reducing it Activity sometimes diminishing the discussion and the classroom environment Activity regularly diminishing the discussion and the classroom environment   Active engagement with and listening to peers, persistently Sincere efforts to interact with peers, normally Limited engagement with peers Rare interaction with peers No interaction with peers      This rubric is significantly based on, and lightly adapted from, one written by another philosophy professor, Jay Odenbaugh.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
