<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>assignments on PHI 14f</title>
    <link>https://chreliot.github.io/phi14f/tags/assignments/</link>
    <description>Recent content in assignments on PHI 14f</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2020 12:37:20 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://chreliot.github.io/phi14f/tags/assignments/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Assignment 2</title>
      <link>https://chreliot.github.io/phi14f/assignments/assignment-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2020 12:37:20 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chreliot.github.io/phi14f/assignments/assignment-2/</guid>
      <description>For this writing assignment, you will think about what you mean by the meaning of life. You&amp;rsquo;ll discuss that in a structured way.
Upload your paper through Blackboard upload, under the Assignments button, any day or time before the end of Monday, December 7.
After a brief, introductory, summarizing paragraph which you should write last, after you&amp;rsquo;ve written all the rest, but place first, construct the following paragraphs. Each numbered item represents a paragraph; it doesn&amp;rsquo;t have to be long.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assignment 1</title>
      <link>https://chreliot.github.io/phi14f/assignments/assignment-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2020 12:17:01 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chreliot.github.io/phi14f/assignments/assignment-1/</guid>
      <description>Your main task is to identify and reconstruct an argument about the meaning of life and then critically evaluate it.
Based on how well you think it works for this task, choose one of the following: (1) the Steve Jobs speech, or (2) a different speech or text you&amp;rsquo;ve found and cleared with me in advance. That will be your “source text.”
From your source text, reconstruct a statement of the form “The meaning of life is …” or “The way to live is ….</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interpreting Grades</title>
      <link>https://chreliot.github.io/phi14f/info/interpreting-grades/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2020 19:55:28 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chreliot.github.io/phi14f/info/interpreting-grades/</guid>
      <description>This note about grading and interpreting grades just adds some detail to what the course syllabus already says about grading.
 4-point scale Writing assignment grades Test grades Overall course grades    4-point scale Grades in this course are assigned and calculated using Hofstra&amp;rsquo;s 4-point scale (described here in the Hofstra Bulletin). Following the Bulletin, the alphabetical grades, including plus (+) and minus (–), have the following 4-point scale values (and vice versa):</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
