<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>topics on PHI 14f</title>
    <link>https://chreliot.github.io/phi14f/tags/topics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in topics on PHI 14f</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2020 11:35:56 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://chreliot.github.io/phi14f/tags/topics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Topic 6: Narrative</title>
      <link>https://chreliot.github.io/phi14f/topics/narrative/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2020 11:35:56 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chreliot.github.io/phi14f/topics/narrative/</guid>
      <description>Here we explore an account of the meaning of life that takes the idea of “meaning” more seriously than do the others we have discussed.
Reading  Joshua Seachris, “The Meaning of Life as Narrative: A New Proposal for Interpreting Philosophy&amp;rsquo;s &amp;lsquo;Primary&amp;rsquo; Question” Philo 12:5–23. via Course Documents on Blackboard.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Topic 5: Happiness</title>
      <link>https://chreliot.github.io/phi14f/topics/happiness/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2020 12:39:02 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chreliot.github.io/phi14f/topics/happiness/</guid>
      <description>From Epicureans to the present, some philosophers have thought that the meaning of life might lie in seeking happiness. We consider a classic expression of this view in anglophone philosophy, and then some criticisms of it.
Reading  John Stuart Mill, from Utilitarianism, 1861. Read, in the following order:  the first section of Chapter 2 “What Utilitarianism Is”, from pages 4 into 5; Chapter 4 “What sort of proof can be given for the principle of utility?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Topic 4: Stoicism</title>
      <link>https://chreliot.github.io/phi14f/topics/stoicism/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 17:42:50 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chreliot.github.io/phi14f/topics/stoicism/</guid>
      <description>The next few topics are specific, positive accounts of the meaning of life. The first one is the ancient — and currently popular — view called Stoicism. Coming to understand what is really good, the Stoics argued, and how the nature of goodness and happiness are rooted in nature, could lead us toward perfect lives.
Reading  Epictetus, The Handbook, PDF available on Blackboard &amp;gt; Course Documents.  See also   “How Not to Panic During the Coronavirus Pandemic: Welcome Hard Times Like a Stoic,” by Brigid Delaney</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Topic 3: Religion and Science</title>
      <link>https://chreliot.github.io/phi14f/topics/relsci/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2020 12:33:11 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chreliot.github.io/phi14f/topics/relsci/</guid>
      <description>Our questions about the meaning of life led to its relationships to two main human institutions from which people seek understanding — religion (especially theology) and science. In this section, we consider the relationship between questions about the meaning of life and the capacities of these institutions.
Reading  Brown, Delwin. 1971. “Process Philosophy and the Question of Life&amp;rsquo;s Meaning Religious Studies 7(1): 13-29, 10 pages of reading. Access through Axinn Library login here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Topic 2: Questions about the Meaning of Life</title>
      <link>https://chreliot.github.io/phi14f/topics/meaning/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 11:55:32 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chreliot.github.io/phi14f/topics/meaning/</guid>
      <description>In Plato&amp;rsquo;s Gorgias we encountered two conflicting versions of the meaning of life, and we discussed philosophy as an approach to questions. Now we turn our focus to what&amp;rsquo;s puzzling about the meaning of life. We can ask “What&amp;rsquo;s the meaning of life?” But that is just the opening move. What are the other questions we might want to ask in order to begin to answer that question? When we face difficult problems, often understanding the question is half the battle!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Topic 1: Philosophy</title>
      <link>https://chreliot.github.io/phi14f/topics/philosophy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2020 12:08:29 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chreliot.github.io/phi14f/topics/philosophy/</guid>
      <description>One of the most prominent living philosophers, Martha Nussbaum, was recently asked “How would you define the role of a philosopher in today’s world?” She answered:
 I wouldn’t. There are so many good ways to engage with the world, and each philosopher should figure it out for herself. I don’t like telling others what to do.
 Still, philosophy has a history. And its history involves people doing specific things and calling them “philosophy,” and not calling other things “philosophy.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
